SUMMARY

Driven software developer graduate from Lambda School's Web Development program with 5 months of experience with Javascript based web development. Ready to get career back on track after dealing with various pandemic related obstacles and working hard to return life back to normal.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Javascript, Java, Python, CSS, HTML

WEB TECHNOLOGIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Node.js, Django, Spring, Express DATABASE AND ORM: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite3, Knex.js, Django ORM, JPA, Hibernate

VERSION CONTROL: Git

DEPLOYMENT: AWS, Heroku, Netlify

PROJECTS

Well-broomed

May 2019 to July 2019

A rental property management platform built to make managing multiple properties simpler.

React | Node.js | PostgreSQL | MaterialUI

- Integrated an emailing system to improve communication among users and their partners using Mailgun API.
- · Architected a secure invitation system that allows users to invite friends and partners to the application using our emailing process
- Designed utilization of an image uploading system to better identify properties using a cloud-based image upload API, Cloudinary
- Utilized UX principles to provide a simple and visual Partner Management component

Repository: https://github.com/well-broomed

Sauti Design Studio v1 July 2019 to Aug. 2019

A web application built to create USSD menu applications for disadvantaged groups in eastern Africa.

React | Node.js | PostgreSQL | React Storm Diagrams

- Coordinated team of 4+ developers by holding daily stand up meetings and directing conversation on areas of importance
- Collaborated with stakeholder of project CTO, Lance Hadley of the NPO Sauti Africa, https://sautiafrica.org
- Implemented an algorithm that parses the diagram built by the frontend and converts it into data that is organized in the PostgreSQL database
- Designed API routes built to handle every function with SQL transactions required by the frontend such as diagram parsing, publishing, and creation.
- Modeled an API route after an USSD Menu to be compatible with Africastalking USSD API

Frontend Repository: https://github.com/labs13-sauti-studio/sauti-studio-FE Backend Repository: https://github.com/labs13-sauti-studio/sauti-studio-BE

EMPLOYMENT

Call Box

Junior Software Developer · Jan. 2020 to May 2020 · Remote

- Modified existing Javascript and Coldfusion codebases to correct errors and improve performance.
- Collaborated with Senior Developers to identify and discuss potential areas of refactoring
- Created and maintained documentation revolving around changes and additions to Vue.js web application software
- Created and maintained documentation revolving about changes and additions to vide application software
 Communicated with the support team on a daily basis to prioritize issues that users were experiencing and then resolving such issues

Lambda School

Team Lead Mar. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Lead daily standup meetings to build communication and connection, facilitate the sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance to improve the team's current project.
- Deliver one-on-one feedback and code review on a daily basis.
- Maintain the version control of the project using Git and the agile methodology

VIP Valet Services

Assistant Event Coordinator - June 2016 to May 2018 - Chicago, IL

- Managed teams ranging from 2-20 employees.
- Established consistent communication with clients regarding their needs and problems.

EDUCATION

Lambda School · May 2018 to Dec. 2018

Lambda School is a 9 month Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that provides an immersive (full-time, 40+ hours/week) hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, software engineering, and web development.